

#### CONTACT

L +57 3104081846

alejokst09@gmail.com

Chía Cundinamarca

www.linkedin.com/in/alejocas02

### **HABILITIES**

Problem-solving skills
Agile team building
Communication Skills
Software Development
Analytical Skills
Decision-making skills
Resource management
Strategic Thinking
Flexibility/Adaptability
Detail Oriented

## **LANGUAGES**

English.

## **EDGAR ALEJANDRO CASTRO TABARES**

### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Electronic Engineer, with extensive experience in Project, Technology, and Service Management. Backend developer, with wide knowledge in REST API, SOAP, Java Spring Boot, SQL, AWS, MySQL, Git, Junit, Mockito, and expert in IoT. Knowledge in AWS, Lambdas, Dynamo DB, Cognito, API Gateway, CloudWatch, S3. With great hability to manage projects with Agile (Scrum) and PMP methodologies and frameworks. Leadership of development, support, and maintenance development teams.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Backend Developer**

Q-vision August 2022- Present

Bogotá - Colombia

1. Backend Java Spring Boot development, reactive programming, hexagonal architecture, use of design patterns. 2. Development under agile methodologies 3. Software development with databases in Cosmos, and MongoDB. 4. Git versioning management. 5. Rabbit MQ. 6. Azure storage account, KeyVault.

# **Backend Developer**

software development cycle.

Lominco Soft February 2021- July 2022

Bogotá - Colombia

1. Backend Java Spring Boot development for front web and front app, use of design patterns. 2. Development under agile methodologies. 3. Software development with databases in MySQL, SQLSERVER and Postgresql. 4. Git versioning management. 5. Redis. 6. AWS, Lambdas, API Gateway, Cognito. 7. Manage a software engineering team, composed of 5 members. Accountable for the delivery on time and with quality of the engineering teams and help eliminate stoppers during

## Development Analyst.

Soluciones Wiga December 2014- February 2021

Chía - Colombia

1. Responsible for the management and execution of IoT Projects in the Agricultural field in Antioquia, Cundinamarca and USA. Accountable for the delivery on time and with quality of the engineering teams and help eliminate stoppers during software development cycle 2. Design and modeling of new products focused on IOT. 3. Manage 2 software engineering teams, each one composed of 6 members. 4. Training in methodologies to improve internal process. 5. Analysis of new products and services. 6. Data interpretation trough Business Intelligence and Business Analytics. 7. Customer Management. 8. Post-sale support. 9. Quality control of products and services developed. 10. Software Development

## Development Engineer.

CETAD Fuerza Aérea, February 2014- December 2014

Rionegro – Colombia

Apps and Software development in languages such as Java, Java EE, Postgresql

# Agent N1, Bancolombia's Support.

Unisys Technical Service September 2012- February 2014

Rionegro – Colombia

Remote technological support to Bancolombia's employees.

### FORMAL EDUCATION

## **MBA** Candidate

**EUDE Business School 2023** 

# Electronic Engineer

U. Católica de Oriente March 2014

### TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS

## Scrum Master Certified

CertiProf December 2022

# AWS Partner: Accreditation (Technical)

Aws training and certification May 2022

## **AWS Technical Essentials**

Aws training and certification May 2022

# Service Management Certified

Universidad de la Sabana April 2021 – June 2021

# Management Skills and Emotional Intelligence Course

Eude Business School April 2021

# Scrum Fundamentals Certified

SCRUMstudy October 2021

## PMP preparation course

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana May 2020 – June 2020